[Adapted from Che Ye Liu Xiang's
novel of the same name]
Where are you going?
I'll take you to see something interesting.
[Episode 12]
[1990]
Is it really because of him?
You bet it is.
I was in the office the other day,
and I saw his dad kneeling down
begging the dean.
It was no use.
He went too far this time.
Lu Xiao Fan didn't even provoke him.
But he didn't have to be expelled for it.
Don't let me see you around here again.
Of all the people with stalls on this street,
who doesn't pay me the management fee?
Think you're special as a college student?
You're just an expelled one now.
Let's go.
Thank you.
I don't need your pity!
Shen Zhi Qin.
I didn't mean for him to hit you.
I didn't think it would turn out like this.
Get lost!
Shen Zhi Qin.
Shen Zhi Qin!
[Financial Trends]
[90s Financial Revolution]
At least take the magazines back.
You're Zhi Qin's classmate?
Yes.
Please, come in.
Hello, sir.
Just leave the stuff and get out.
Zhi Qin.
You always have such a temper.
Why don't you ever learn?
Don't mind him.
You're the first classmate
who's come to visit Zhi Qin.
It shows you're a good kid.
What's your name?
Now you know what shame is?
When you were fighting
and bullying your classmate,
why didn't you feel ashamed then?
Sir...
My name is Lu Xiao Fan.
Back then, Zhi Qin's grades
were always very good.
I don't know why he didn't get into
a top school during the entrance exam.
The university happened to be
expanding its vocational enrollment.
That year, a truck crushed this leg of mine.
The compensation money
was just enough to pay for his tuition.
You know how universities are.
They're full of rich kids.
Zhi Qin is very competitive.
He always wants to wear nice clothes.
When he's short on money, he works.
He sells magazines.
Xiao Fan.
Don't take it to heart with Zhi Qin.
He's just very proud.
Zhi Qin...
He's not a bad person.
I hope you'll come and visit him often.
I will, Uncle.
- Uncle...
- Xiao Fan.
You've misunderstood me.
I could never take your money.
Who wants your charity?
I'm just paying for these magazines.
I don't need your pity!
Xiao Fan.
Well? Are you satisfied
with how I stood up for you?
Bei Lv Qing hasn't been
this high-profile in all his years at school.
Lu Xiao Fan, can you stop
bringing this junk into the building?
Xiao Fan, there's another
cardboard box over there.
During his school years,
Lu Xiao Fan worked hard to save money.
But he knew that for Shen Zhi Qin,
this help was just a drop in the bucket.
He could only spend more time
with Shen Zhi Qin's father,
even if it was just to chat.
Lu Xiao Fan, have you had enough?
Can't you just get lost?
Oh, Zhi Qin!
- You're the one who's had enough!
- Dad!
He's just here to show off.
You've already won, Lu Xiao Fan.
I know I'm not from the same world as you.
You don't have to humiliate me like this.
Sit down!
Xiao Fan has had a hard life, too.
Lu Xiao Fan belongs to a group of people
whose purpose in life
was not the meaning of life,
nor the pursuit of life,
but survival itself.
So, maybe one day,
I'll be thrown back
to my hometown in the mountains.
Don't you hate Bei Lv Qing?
Don't you hate the Bei family?
The most important thing is to survive.
And then strive to live well.
Then how do you think we can survive?
And live well?
Zhi Qin.
I know you secretly
gave the old man a lot of money
to buy medicine.
But that's not your responsibility.
I didn't know it was bone cancer.
None of you told me.
What if there was another way?
Zhi Qin.
What are your plans for the future?
You're right.
China's future lies in the economy.
I believe you.
So, I'm planning to sell this ancestral house.
I'll go out and make a name for myself.
This house is the last thing you have.
You're really going to sell it?
I'll definitely make something of myself.
What I want,
I must earn for myself.
Xiao Fan is here. Sit down.
[Document Folder]
This guy doesn't even have an account.
Why the hell is he reading
the securities paper all day?
[Securities Paper]
- Hello?
- Xiao Fan, it's me.
- Is it a good time to talk?
- Yes, it's fine.
Did you lose money again?
Actually, I didn't.
It's just that it keeps going up.
I don't know if I should sell.
You didn't invest all your money, did you?
Yeah.
Maybe I should sell some to pay the rent.
The price of rice is going to rise.
Rice is going up?
Wheat will probably be the same.
I've seen it in the newspapers lately, too.
I think there's still room for it to rise.
Hang in there.
Is your address the same? I'll send you an IOU.
- There's really no need.
- Keep the IOU.
I, Shen Zhi Qin, will definitely pay you back.
You're finally here.
Hey, Xiao Fan.
This is your fiancé Bei Lv Qing's...
brother-in-law.
Hello.
I'm Bei Lv Qing's...
brother-in-law.
Over the next few years,
Shen Zhi Qin's business boomed.
After Xiao Fan came to Lin Gang,
behind Bei Lv Qing's back,
he thrived in the securities market.
What's so important
that we had to meet in person?
A lovers' quarrel?
- If Bei Lv Qing knew you were here...
- Li Wen Xi.
Did he go to your office today?
Li Wen Xi is teaming up with Lu Tao
to take down Bei Lv Qing.
You're just going to tell me that easily?
He only proposed the idea today.
I would've told you even if you didn't ask.
I know I owe you, Lu Xiao Fan.
Maybe I shouldn't have told you.
I think you hate Bei Lv Qing.
Now that I've told you,
it's become your burden.
You decide for yourself.
If you hate the man, then don't say a word.
If you don't hate him,
tell him Li Wen Xi is coming after him.
I don't hate him.
But I...
really want to hate him.
And I really want him to hate me.
Then don't tell him.
But...
Li Wen Xi can't handle my brother.
Even with Lu Tao, they can't.
Don't overestimate Bei Lv Qing.
Li Wen Xi has capital and is ruthless.
Why wouldn't he be able to handle it?
Just wait for Bei Lv Qing to go broke.
Last time Lu Tao and I were chatting,
he mentioned a possibility.
That is, if they could find out
what futures my brother bought,
and how many lots,
and at what point he opens positions,
they might be able to
use limited funds in a short period of time
to make my brother's account blow up.
Oh?
He's not just talking about a possibility.
Actually, he's always wanted to do that.
He wants my brother to feel
what it's like to plummet
and have nothing left.
To feel how you felt back then.
What does that have to do with me?
The futures market is a place
where the big fish eat the small fish.
Everyone who enters the market is a fish.
It just so happens that
Bei Lv Qing is a big, fat fish.
It's not surprising that Lu Tao targeted him.
If Lu Tao could accurately know
what kind of futures my brother bought,
how many lots,
and at what point he adds to his positions,
could you and him make my brother go broke?
Are you serious?
Is my brother still playing games?
You mean Lu Xiao Ping?
It doesn't seem like Bei Lv Qing
is doing your brother a favor
by letting him learn the ropes.
He probably just wants
your brother around to play games.
The young master has plenty of money.
Spending over 10,000 a month
to see your brother so smug...
It's worth it just for the fun.
Lv Qing is not that shallow.
He never trusted Li Wen Xi.
Goodness...
I didn't know you and Wen Xi were so close.
We're childhood friends.
No wonder you're doing business together.
Isn't this all for you?
Be careful.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
- Let's go inside.
- Okay.
Xiao Fan found out?
Then you have to explain it to him.
Li Wen Xi went to see Lu Xiao Fan today.
What does Li Wen Xi know?
He probably doesn't know yet.
But I don't dare tell Xiao Fan.
I'm afraid Li Wen Xi will fish for information.
Then...
Then Lu Xiao Fan will be so heartbroken.
Why did it have to be Song Qian Yu?
Anyone else would have done the job.
Why did it have to be Li Wen Xi's friend?
Th-This is like stabbing Xiao Fan in the heart.
Li Wen Xi is very smart.
If it wasn't from his friend,
he wouldn't believe the information.
After all this is over,
I'll tell Xiao Fan everything.
I trust him.
Xiao Fan.
I might have to go back to Yunjing.
I'll be back after the New Year.
Uncle.
I have to go back to Lin Gang.
I'll take my leave now.
Do you have urgent business in Lin Gang?
What if Bei Lv Xin doesn't want a divorce?
What will you do?
What else can I do?
Then don't bring up the divorce.
Since he moved to Lin Gang,
you've been doing the cleaning?
I know exactly what is kept where.
I'll never misplace anything.
Our housekeeper has very good habits.
She never touches things randomly.
Things stay exactly where they are put.
But my brother isn't that stupid.
You have to use Li Wen Xi as bait first.
Bei Lv Qing is the best, all right?
- Can you stop repeating that?
- I trust Xiao Fan's judgment.
Look.
The micro-camera is inside here.
But are you sure
we'll definitely receive the signal?
Bei Lv Qing's planned trades...
Only the last one might be the real one.
If you can't guarantee it stays
right where Bei Lv Qing sits,
then we won't see anything.
How about this?
When you get abroad,
give me your account details.
Once the job is done,
I'll transfer your commission for this job.
I'm sure you'll live
a very comfortable life abroad.
No need.
Zhi Qin.
Close out all my accounts.
I want to withdraw all the money.
Are you sure you want to close them?
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
The millions you made from corn
could turn into tens of millions.
One more thing.
After you finish this job,
find a way to escape immediately.
You're overthinking it.
Do you really think they're all-powerful?
Besides, the Songnan Gang
and the Yunjing group are fighting fiercely.
We have people backing us up.
Taking down Bei Lv Qing first is just a way
to show respect to those above.
Even if the CSRC regulates the futures market,
it's not necessarily up to
Bei Lv Qing's father to decide.
Mr. Lu.
Promise me.
After this job is done,
take Zhi Qin and leave the north.
Otherwise...
I'll back out.
Fine.
I promise.
Zhi Qin.
If Lu Tao doesn't leave, you must leave.
Xiao Fan, trust me.
Bei Lv Qing isn't that capable.
Actually, even if we pull this off,
it won't truly destroy him.
Then why are you doing all this?
You're not even taking the money.
But it will definitely be a huge blow to him.
He has never failed in his life.
This failure will surely stay with him forever.
- So, you're doing it to...
- I don't know.
Maybe I just want him to remember me.
I don't expect anything
to happen between us in this lifetime.
I just hope
he remembers me for the rest of his life.
Even if it's with hatred.
Lv Qing.
Isn't this too risky?
After all, Li Wen Xi is no small player.
You were the one who persuaded me
to enter this market.
Why are you the one getting cold feet now?
Lv Qing, you've never been such a risk-taker.
What's going on with you?
Lu Xiao Fan is determined
to divorce Bei Lv Xin.
What are you talking about?
I'm going to marry Lu Xiao Fan.
Bei Lv Qing, are you crazy?
Your parents will never...
Only this way will I have the leverage
to properly protect Lu Xiao Fan.
It's hard to explain.
That's why I asked them to take a look.
What?
Why did the potato price go up?
It's Lu Xiao Fan.
Attention all passengers
for flight YG1213 bound for Porto.
Your flight is now boarding.
Lu Xiao Fan didn't think for a second
that he could take down Bei Lv Qing in one go.
He wasn't as optimistic
as Lu Tao and Shen Zhi Qin.
He was fleeing with a sense
of desperate urgency,
knowing full well he would never return.
If it weren't for Bei Lv Qing,
Lu Xiao Fan might have been
an ordinary farmer like his father.
He wouldn't be this kind,
nor would he be this bad.
He'd have a hardworking,
feisty wife just like his mother.
They'd have one child, and then two more.
A life of poverty, but lively.
Lu Xiao Fan didn't hate
that he had become twisted.
But he hated that
he was twisted and yet all alone.
He didn't want to hate his mother,
nor was he willing to hate Lu Xiao Ping.
He certainly wouldn't hate Bei Lv Xin.
But he had to hate the man
who gave him dreams time and again,
only to snatch them away.
When he thought of that man,
he felt nothing but hate.
His legs would tremble at the thought.
When he thought of that man,
he couldn't stop thinking of him.
He wanted the man to remember him forever.
Hello? Who is this?
If you don't speak, I'm hanging up.
Zhi Qin, it's me.
It's me, Lu Xiao Fan.
You...
[Shen Zhi Qin]
Mr. Lu Tao, you are officially
under arrest for disrupting the market.
Please come with us.
I did it all by myself.
It had nothing to do with anyone else.
[Lu Tao was sentenced to five years
of imprisonment for market disruption.]
[Bei Lv Qing was investigated and his earnings
from illegal investments confiscated.]
[Spain, 1996]
[Chinatown]
What can I get for you?
I'll have one bone soup...
and one seafood porridge.
Sure.
No spring onions, please.
Would you like some celery, then?
Tell me, are you really that stupid?
You used your Portuguese account
to wire money to Shen Zhi Qin.
You're basically telling us
exactly where you are.
Why even bother running?
He started it.
The way you chose to make me
remember you is truly unique.
I say, Lv Qing, why don't we
stop wasting our breath?
Let's just kill him.
Where are my soup and porridge?
Big Bro, here's the porridge.
I say, Lu Xiao Fan,
first, you nearly bankrupted us
and gave us a real scare.
Then you made us exhausted
from searching for you.
Now you're acting all friendly with us.
But have you thought about it?
You've offended so many people...
and caused such a huge mess.
How do you think your family is doing now?
Big Bro...
Is what Zi Yang said true?
Your brother might not pursue it,
but that doesn't mean the others won't.
A man should answer for his own actions.
I'll take responsibility for my own mess.
Lu Xiao Fan, calm down.
Let's get married.
You really are a piece of work.
I was just teasing you,
and you took it seriously.
If we were really seeking revenge,
would we be wasting our time here with you?
I really...
Big Bro...
Weren't you...
supposed to be getting engaged?
If Lv Qing didn't need to
make enough money to run away with you,
why else would he agree to trade futures?
He only played nice with that woman
to fool his mom and Li Wen Xi for a few days.
You've got quite a temper.
You nearly made us lose our minds
playing along with you.
Even my old man's secret stash
was almost blown because of you.
If you hadn't run so fast, you'd be dead meat.
Your cooking hasn't changed.
You'll have to make porridge for me
for the rest of your life.
Are you willing?
I am.
Let's go.
Bei Lv Qing, do you take
Lu Xiao Fan to be your partner?
In the presence of God,
to love and cherish him,
to be faithful and caring of him,
to respect him in health and sickness,
until the end of your life?
I will.
Lu Xiao Fan, do you take
Bei Lv Qing as your partner?
In the presence of God,
to love and cherish him,
in health and sickness, to respect...
I will!
Congratulations.
You may now kiss each other.
Lu Xiao Fan.
I've realized...
this is the first time
I've looked at you like this.
Big Bro.
Why are you up before the alarm went off?
You need to remove
the tough fibers from the celery.
Otherwise, they'll get stuck in your teeth.
Like this.
Then you do it.
Oh, and boil the water before adding the rice.
Otherwise, it'll stick to the pot.
Also, the rice should be soaked in advance.
That way, it'll cook until it's soft.
It seems I'll have to work a bit harder then.
Just tell me what you want to eat.
I'll cook it.
If I had worked a bit harder last night,
you wouldn't have so much to say today.
Let's go to France for New Year's.
We'll see the Eiffel Tower
you've always dreamed of.
Big Bro, I have something to tell you.
Don't be mad.
All right.
My mom said...
she wants us to go home together
for the New Year.
My mom said...
newlyweds have to pay respects
to their ancestors together
to be truly recognized.
Okay.